

### Profile

From a young age, I knew I would have a future with technology. This idea probably formed from the many groundings I received when my parents found me on the computer past curfew. In industry, this passion remains. I constantly push myself to understand new technologies to deliver the best experiences possible. There is certainly a mountain more to learn, and more problems to solve; knowing this is what keeps me enthusiastic and drives me. I am currently focused on delivering high quality web applications with Typescript built on the latest technologies.

# Employment History

## Software Developer at ASICS RaceRoster

March 2020

At RaceRoster I'm helping lead the push to building with modern technologies. We are achieving this by implementing a GraphQL layer on-top of our existing resources to decouple our front-end stack from the legacy PHP application.

### Lead Software Developer at Sport-Travel

November 2018 — 2020

I led the software department at Sport-Travel where I pushed the team to develop scalable lightweight, progressive web applications. I approached leadership by encouraging idea sharing and regular employee participation. While also trying to lead by going above and beyond.

### **Software Developer at Sport-Travel**

May 2017 — November 2018

Hired alongside two developers to shape the future at Sport-Travel, and help the company endeavour towards a technology-centered business approach. I adopted and owned the legacy codebase and the transition into more sustainable development patterns and technologies.

### Contract Web Developer at DukeToyCo

August 2015 — July 2016

Web developer for DukeToyCo. Website design, online marketing, social media presence, and online branding.

### Education

**Studied Computer Science, Western University** 

2013 — 2017

#### **Details**

London

Canada

519-328-2984

james@jamesvan.ca

#### Links

Blog

Github

LinkedIn

**Twitter** 

#### **Skills**

**Typescript** 

Node

Vue

React

GraphQL

PHP

SQL

Docker

Google Cloud

**Github Actions**